Have you tried to register your device in Microsoft Intune?
For example, a Windows 10 or Windows 11 device.
Another device never should opt in Microsoft Intune.
But the device is actually should in IntraID.
So, yeah, it's a Windows 10 device.
This could be a Windows 11 device.
And you've tried to register a device in Intune,
but it's not sure enough.
So let's go to our IntraID, for example,
we have all our devices in IntraID.
You can set a device to see 001,
which has just been recognized.
You can see the register is suspended.
So this is going to take some time.
But at the same time, if I go to Microsoft Intune,
you can see we only have just one device.
And the other device is not sure enough.
So once it's actually the issue.
So if I go back again to my device,
if I go back into my C001,
then we got only verify this in EventViewer.
Because there's a policy,
there's a group policy that has been configured
in the domain controller
that I totally registered the files automatically
to Microsoft Intune.
So what right now you can see when I go to
on an EventViewer here, you need to go to applications
and service logs, go to Microsoft, Windows,
and then set for device management
enterprise diagnostic provider.
And here we can see the admin.
So if you can see we have a lot of error opposite here.
So let's start from here.
You can see it says no migration needed.
Okay, that is okay.
But here you can see it says Auto, MDM
and role device credentials field.
The system try to delete the join of a driver
that is not joined.
So we keep getting the same error message
and this device could not be joined to MDM.
And one of the problems is this.
I've seen this at a level apart.
So I'm not trying to do this video
to help someone who is having that issue.
Before someone could join his device
to Microsoft Intune, that person must have a license.
If that person does not have a license,
that person will not be able to join his device
to Microsoft Intune.
For example, if I just go, let me just enter a CMD
and here you can see this is the host demo of the device.
If I see who am I, you can see this is actually Kelvin Johnson.
But the issue is Kelvin Johnson does not have
a Microsoft Intune license.
So if I go to my domain controller
and I start active directory users and computers,
here you can see for example,
if I go to my domain and go to users,
here you can see we have the account of Kelvin Johnson.
And you can see Kelvin belongs to the kelv global ICT.com
and Simon Johnson belongs to the kelv global tech.
Well, the kelv global tech is the right name
that have the license to Microsoft Intune
which means that if I switch, for example,
if I decide right now, I want to lock out of,
let me just sign out or ask Kelvin Johnson
and then let's switch to a different user.
So let's switch right now to, for example,
I'm going to use the account of Simon dot Johnson
and I just hit into the password and it's enter.
So let's switch for Simon to log on
and then we can now see if this device is registered
in Microsoft Intune.
So after I log on to the device
and I go back again to events if you are,
here in the device management enterprise
and I check admin, you can see we have some extra information
let me just try to bring this down.
You can see we are seeing more information
now and I've seen less of error message
and the error message is actually different.
But if I scroll up,
you can see we are now having some of the session
and then we start off the pressure completeness successfully.
So when I go back again to my,
to the intro idea, you can see when I do a refresh,
you can see that the device is 001 is now available
and says the MDM is Microsoft Intune
like the other one says it's known
and this is a totally core management.
Then if we go back into Intune self,
here you can see we have core managed
and you can see that the device just appeared in Intune,
it's not evaluated, it's gonna take some time
for this to be evaluated.
So the bottom line is this.
If you are seeing a device in Intune,
probably the user is actually trying to sign in
with an account that does not have a license.
So what you need to do is to assign a license
to that user and the user will be able to log on.
And apart from that, you should make sure
that the user is using the right domain name.
Probably in your domain environment,
you may have different domain accounts.
So if you assign a user it domain accounts,
those notes, that does not correspond
with Microsoft Intune domain
or the domain that is ready started Intune,
like for example, if I go to,
let me just enter DNS here, DNS zones.
Let me see, let me see, let me see domain name, sorry.
Here you can see we have some domain verified domain name.
So the verified domain name,
which is the care of global tech is the verified domain name,
which I have assigned some license to.
So the user is trying to use a different domain name
may not be able to add the device to Microsoft Intune.
My name is Kelvin, Johnson and please don't forget
to subscribe to my YouTube channel for more IT related video
like this.
And if you haven't any issue with consigns Microsoft Intune,
please don't forget to send me an email
or leave a comment in the comment section of this video.
And I'll reply to you as quick as possible.
Bye.